<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Antomor</title>
    <link>https://antomor.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Antomor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 16:27:12 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://antomor.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Iterators &amp; Generators in Python</title>
      <link>https://antomor.com/blog/python-iterators-generators/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 16:27:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://antomor.com/blog/python-iterators-generators/</guid>
      <description>This post aims to describe the basic mechanisms behind iterators and generators.
Iterator protocol As in many programming languages, Python allows to iterate over a collection. The iteration mechanism is often useful when we need to scan a sequence, operation that is very common in programming. In Python the iterator protocol involves two components: an iterable and an iterator.
Iterable The iterable is the container through which we want to iterate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Angular Dynamic Content</title>
      <link>https://antomor.com/blog/angular-dynamic-content/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 10:51:42 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://antomor.com/blog/angular-dynamic-content/</guid>
      <description>In many cases we would change the content of a component dynamically, like for instance, to allow the user to change view or to let the children render the data retrieved and elaborated from its parent component. Here below we are going to show some techniques to create a component without deciding how the data would be shown. According with the application needs, each technique has its own strengths, but all of them encourage component reusability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSP and CORS</title>
      <link>https://antomor.com/blog/csp-and-cors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 10:51:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://antomor.com/blog/csp-and-cors/</guid>
      <description>What is CSP CSP stands for Content Security Policy and it is a security mechanism that helps to protect or mitigate some common attacks such as XSS (Cross-site scripting). It can be set by means of Content-Security-Policy HTTP header or using HTML meta tag.
HTTP header:
Content-Security-Policy: policy HTML Meta tag:
&amp;lt;meta http-equiv=&amp;#34;Content-Security-Policy&amp;#34; content=&amp;#34;policy&amp;#34;&amp;gt; A policy describes a set of directives composed by the area in which the rule is applied and the rule itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Angular and Rxjs Http Requests: Common scenarios</title>
      <link>https://antomor.com/blog/angular-rxjs-http-requests/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 19:40:48 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://antomor.com/blog/angular-rxjs-http-requests/</guid>
      <description>Any modern web application needs soon or later to perform some http request to retrieve data. Here below I&amp;rsquo;ll describe some common scenario and how to perform such requests using RxJS.
Single request The most common scenario, no special rxjs handling, since that Angular provides an Http service that returns an Observable.
services.getItems().subscribe(); Is that easy? Yes. In the particular example, I assumed the http service call was inside the service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git: Move Files Retaining History</title>
      <link>https://antomor.com/blog/git-move-file-with-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 12:28:03 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://antomor.com/blog/git-move-file-with-history/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes ago we need to create a new product, that shares many functionalities with the existing one. The first idea was to extract some of the code in a library, to be then imported and used independently in the two projects.
After creating the repository for the library, the first action I would have done was copying the files from one repo to another. Well, it works like a charm, it’s fast and it doesn’t require any particular expertise, a normal drag and drop operation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mongodb Query Profiler</title>
      <link>https://antomor.com/blog/mongodb-query-profiler/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2019 18:06:38 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://antomor.com/blog/mongodb-query-profiler/</guid>
      <description>Some months ago, I was creating a web page to show some aggregated data, but I soon noticed the API used to retrieve the data was very slow. After investigating on the possible issue, we discovered the bottleneck: the database. The solution was to re-structure the data to make it consumable from a web page.
Although I had used sometimes the SQLServer profiler, I had no experience about MongoDB profiler, so here below the steps involved to analyse a MongoDB query.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security Headers on Static Websites</title>
      <link>https://antomor.com/blog/security-headers-on-static-websites/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2019 10:56:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://antomor.com/blog/security-headers-on-static-websites/</guid>
      <description>When I started this blog, I evaluated many options:
 blogging platform vs static-generated website self-hosted vs hosted solutions costs and many more.  I ended up trying to build something very simple, consisting in a static website hosted on GitHub Pages. With this solution, I have been able to cut the cost on any host solution, since that, being a dev, I am quite comfortable in writing in a text editor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SPA deployment with GitLab</title>
      <link>https://antomor.com/blog/gitlab-cd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 10:53:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://antomor.com/blog/gitlab-cd/</guid>
      <description>In the last projects, I started using GitLab, not only as git repository server, but also as DevOps platform. So here I am going to describe a very simple architecture to deploy a single page application using Docker and docker-compose, nginx. In this specific project I used also dotnet-core for the back-end API and VueJS as front-end framework, but it is language-agnostic, meaning that you can replace whatever back-end or front-end you prefer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Browser Extension Development</title>
      <link>https://antomor.com/blog/browser-extension/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 17:15:01 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://antomor.com/blog/browser-extension/</guid>
      <description>Web extensions or browser plugins can be used to improve browser functionalities. The following examples summarize the different goals they can have:
 no-script - to block script served from not-trusted domains ublock Origin - it is &amp;ldquo;a wide-spectrum blocker&amp;rdquo; dark-mode - it changes the appearance of web pages React Developer Tools - to inspect react-specific properties of a page that makes use of React.  Anatomy of an extension The main components of a browser extension are:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s Test</title>
      <link>https://antomor.com/blog/lets-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2019 10:48:40 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://antomor.com/blog/lets-test/</guid>
      <description>Preamble This article is not intended to cover the whole testing process due to its vastness. Having a glance at its Wikipedia page could give an idea of it. I am going to cover only the tip of the iceberg, but it is important to remind that bugs cannot be eliminated from the software, but in contrast, they must be discovered as soon as possible.
 The higher is the time passed since the bug come into the system, the higher is the cost to fix it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started With My Website :-)</title>
      <link>https://antomor.com/blog/why/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 21:40:25 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://antomor.com/blog/why/</guid>
      <description>Here in this post, I am going to explain why I am starting writing something on INTERNET and what I am going to share. I perfectly know that there are so many sites today, describing almost everything, but these are only some of the reasons which drive me at this point:
 to improve my language skills; to improve my online presence; to receive feedbacks (feedback is the key to grow up); to share what I do (and how, I am going to list also some of my biggest mistakes).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
